[{"id": "5fe3edf68b5801b8f54a7fb5", "question": "What is the museum in Plymouth, Massachusetts that replicates the original settlement of the Plymouth Colony?", "answer": "Plimouth Plantation", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4de7906d333868d34d716", "question": "What was the Great Western Schism?", "answer": "When more than one pope claimed authority over the Roman Catholic church.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d118174fea7fe947a22281", "question": "What metal has the chemical symbol Pb?", "answer": "Lead", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008bc9cf842fa4c4ba969a", "question": "In which Verdi opera does Violetta sing \"Sempre libera\"?", "answer": "La Traviata", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c147", "question": "How many individual stitches are on a regulation baseball ball?", "answer": "216", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c885", "question": "How many arms does a squid have?", "answer": "Ten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c188", "question": "Which school's football players run onto the field behind \"Ralphie\", a live bison?", "answer": "University of Colorado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339535", "question": "Who played Lois in \"Lois & Clark: The New Adventures of Superman\"?", "answer": "Teri Hatcher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db78230ab2c8f322317ff2", "question": "Which author wrote about the Cornish seaside boarding school Malory Towers?", "answer": "Enid Blyton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b5c", "question": "Who played Babe Ruth in the 1992 film \"The Babe\"?", "answer": "John Goodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a539", "question": "Which US state's highest mountain is Mt. Rainier?", "answer": "Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b23ae328f1a2238a7cb2b3b", "question": "What is the southernmost continent?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a667", "question": "What land mass juts into the northern end of Delaware Bay?", "answer": "Cape May", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a52b", "question": "The majority of the Sierra Nevada Mountains are located in which state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a416", "question": "What West Coast city was home to Jack Murphy Stadium?", "answer": "San Diego", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a307", "question": "Who played the role of David Duchovny's daughter on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Madeleine Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b851", "question": "In chess, which piece only moves diagonally?", "answer": "The bishop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5922049aa4edfd43a087ade6", "question": "Butter bean is another name for which type of bean?", "answer": "Lima", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa55a3c73aa70ea0b70b24", "question": "Sahti is a type of beer that is traditionally flavored with juniper and it is most likely found in which country?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae9363574a5ce6b56b823a", "question": "What was Queen Victoria's first name?", "answer": "Alexandrina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7bfe0877e98cb9777896b", "question": "What country borders the Caspian Sea, Persian Gulf, and Gulf of Oman?", "answer": "Iran", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0adf0e662d71a53650fb5", "question": "Who became famous for painting New Mexico landscapes from her Model A Ford?", "answer": "Georgia O\u2019Keeffe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6998f20565ad31a57c748", "question": "What were the names of the Doberman Pinschers on \"Magnum P.I.\"?", "answer": "Zeus and Apollo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c206", "question": "What year were the Olympic Games hosted in the US for the first time?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c888", "question": "What scoop out cirques, coombs, and corries?", "answer": "Glaciers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4ea3606d333868d34d75a", "question": "In what year did Nazi Germany open its first concentration camp?", "answer": "1933", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d2", "question": "The single-portion takeout named \"bento\" originated from which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3ac", "question": "Which Kingdom is Greenland a part of?", "answer": "The Kingdom of Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb00", "question": "What is the correct name for the occupation in which someone mends shoes?", "answer": "Cobbler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918a", "question": "How many keys does a baby grand piano have?", "answer": "88", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a495", "question": "Which Australian state borders all other mainland states?", "answer": "South Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be13", "question": "What specific animal appeared above the \"Don't Tread on Me\" motto on early American flags?", "answer": "A rattlesnake", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a97a", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Great Khural?", "answer": "Mongolia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c89f877e98cb977789e9", "question": "Which US state is home to Theodore Roosevelt National Park?", "answer": "North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339456", "question": "What film earned Henry Fonda his first Oscar for Best Actor?", "answer": "On Golden Pond", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339125", "question": "\"Samson and Delilah\" is an opera by which French composer?", "answer": "Camille Saint-Sa\u00ebns", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4a", "question": "Who was the first US president to be assassinated?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "592ead28f83302ff91e46477", "question": "Which play is generally accepted to be Shakespeare's last, fully completed play before his death?", "answer": "The Tempest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3b0", "question": "Who was the first woman to win an Oscar Best Actress in 1929?", "answer": "Janet Gaynor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a32f", "question": "What was the debut album of the band \"Belle and Sebastian\"?", "answer": "Tigermilk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133958a", "question": "What male actor plays the lead role in the 2005 movie \"The Island\"?", "answer": "Ewen McGregor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e16506d333868d34d727", "question": "Who wrote \"The Communist Manifesto\"?", "answer": "Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa66", "question": "What is the capital of Kuwait?", "answer": "Kuwait City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133904a", "question": "What did the Lady of the Lake give King Arthur?", "answer": "Excalibur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b358df35db0d66a186cb565", "question": "Burt Reynolds played the role of who on the TV show \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "Blacksmith Quint Asper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb83", "question": "What citrus beverage has used the ad slogan \"Open a Bottle of Sunshine\"?", "answer": "Sunny Delight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6b653fb6c85e9e634ff48", "question": "The fear of men is known as what?", "answer": "Androphobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c859", "question": "What are the only two consecutive prime numbers?", "answer": "2 and 3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e95", "question": "What movie did the villain Amon Goeth appear in?", "answer": "Schindler's List", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909d062bb53d1af658864fb", "question": "What year was the computer worm, \"Father Christmas\", released into the world?", "answer": "1988", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f0", "question": "In which US state was rapper \"Eminem\" born?", "answer": "Missouri", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab3", "question": "Karakul and Dorset are types of what?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133957a", "question": "What year was Sarah Polley's, All I Want for Christmas released?", "answer": "2002", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949d", "question": "What actor played the role of Captain James T. Kirk in the original Star Trek series?", "answer": "William Shatner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a5e", "question": "Jazz musicians sometimes refer to which instrument as a \"licorice stick\"?", "answer": "Clarinet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5e72cbb2d0874f1a5e2d1c22", "question": "How many years is a \"Copyright Protection\" granted in the United States to an author after their death?", "answer": "70 years", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad7", "question": "Which river is dammed by the Hoover Dam?", "answer": "Colorado River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f74dfa9e54d890926f701", "question": "According to Russian law, a homeless person must be where after 10 pm?", "answer": "At home", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b9", "question": "What is the main ingredient used to make pesto sauce?", "answer": "Basil", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea380fff048f679a45ab20", "question": "What is the scientific name for the job or role an organism plays in its habitat?", "answer": "Niche", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af30", "question": "From what terrible disease did Robert the Bruce suffer?", "answer": "Leprosy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab75", "question": "What is the capital of Mauritius?", "answer": "Port Louis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c482", "question": "Are polar bears carnivores or omnivores?", "answer": "Carnivores", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fef63486ce05a3942286e63", "question": "What was the first magazine to sell 1 billion copies in a single year?", "answer": "TV Guide", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc94", "question": "What sport's lingo uses the term \"Scrum\"?", "answer": "Rugby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00f", "question": "The Northern Mariana Islands became a US territory during what war?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e4d", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"Steel\"?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe5265c1bf59ab7d2e380f6", "question": "What is the coldest permanently inhabited town on Earth?", "answer": "Oymyakon, Russia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc0d1c469bb8041d07a058", "question": "Which country did ices or sorbets originate in?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133985c", "question": "In the movie \"Howl's Moving Castle\", Calcifer was voiced by which actor?", "answer": "Billy Crystal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339617", "question": "Adam West portrayed which superhero on television?", "answer": "Batman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76f73eec85e375820b2ea", "question": "What is the only walled city north of Mexico?", "answer": "Quebec City, Quebec, Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339262", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's dog in the movie \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9335574a5ce6b56b8237", "question": "Juventas was the Roman goddess of what?", "answer": "Youth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b34ce662d71a53650fdd", "question": "Who wrote the opening line, \"All children, except one, grow up\"?", "answer": "J.M. Barrie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febb7107e83c707845b212e", "question": "What is another word for involuntary muscle twitches?", "answer": "Myoclonus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600b86681d8c1817608d53e4", "question": "What does the \"E\" stand for in Chuck E. Cheese?", "answer": "Entertainment (Restaurant founder, Nolan Bushnell, happens to be the founder of Atari.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f6", "question": "St. Croix, St. John and St. Thomas are part of what US territory?", "answer": "Virgin Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338963", "question": "Under what pseudonym did Charlotte Bronte first publish \"Jane Eyre\"?", "answer": "Currer Bell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133947e", "question": "In the movie \"Legally Blonde\", what LSAT score does Elle need to get into Harvard?", "answer": "175", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e6", "question": "What is the official name of the Michelin Man?", "answer": "Bibendum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd9", "question": "What year was Mark Wahlberg born?", "answer": "1971", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008de03f4f3bc4a292f8627", "question": "Who wrote \"Letter from Birmingham Jail\"?", "answer": "Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. -- The civil rights leader wrote the letter as an open letter on April 16, 1963.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab78", "question": "Mauritius is an island country located in which ocean?", "answer": "Indian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b803", "question": "What is traditionally broken at the end of a Jewish wedding?", "answer": "A glass", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbca", "question": "Who was the first head coach to win three Super Bowls?", "answer": "Chuck Noll", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5954e9c08e82ccaf3b9a67bc", "question": "What food group is a cucumber technically in?", "answer": "Fruits", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f95abb855722f97b22684d3", "question": "What is the name of Han Solo\u2019s ship?", "answer": "Millennium Falcon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c74", "question": "What book did William Peter Blatty write with the $10,000 he won from \"You Bet Your Life\"?", "answer": "The Exorcist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c094", "question": "What are Common Darter and Southern Hawker types of?", "answer": "Dragonflies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a9e94177ccba3ffe45786ce", "question": "How old was Buddy Holly when he died in a plane crash in 1959?", "answer": "22 years old", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339921", "question": "Actress Carrie Fisher and singer Edie Brickell have both been married to what musician?", "answer": "Paul Simon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e1478f9dd42e4a67cb8d3ec", "question": "What automobile brand invented the three point seatbelt, then waived their patent rights, allowing competitors to copy?", "answer": "Volvo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594d07ba1a1c922dd1ac64bb", "question": "Who was the Greek god of sleep?", "answer": "Hypnos", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a6", "question": "Who originally designed the Washington Monument?", "answer": "Robert Mills", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab8", "question": "What nationality was the chemist Alfred Nobel?", "answer": "Swedish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c46", "question": "Prior to becoming a rapper, what popular Canadian TV show did Drake star in?", "answer": "Degrassi: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392dc", "question": "What duo's debut album was titled \"Wednesday Morning, 3 AM\"?", "answer": "Simon & Garfunkel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb6947e83c707845b2129", "question": "What is the name for the boundary around a black hole?", "answer": "Event Horizon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab969186faa38a764be520", "question": "What company did Mercedes-Benz partner with to develop the Smart car?", "answer": "Swatch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c49b", "question": "Bubble wrap was invented accidentally by researchers who were trying to develop a new type of what?", "answer": "A 3-dimensional wallpaper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea8", "question": "Which French King Louis was called the Sun King?", "answer": "Louis XIV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c574", "question": "Which element has the chemical symbol \"No\"?", "answer": "Nobelium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963a", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Megara?", "answer": "Hercules'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015dedefe83fe1f2a824b73", "question": "How many people died in the Korean War?", "answer": "Two million", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133966b", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Springfield's comic book store?", "answer": "Android's Dungeon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c4", "question": "Lake Tiberias is more commonly known as the Sea of what?", "answer": "Galilee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0dd", "question": "Who was Humphrey Bogarts 4th wife?\u00a0", "answer": "Lauren Bacall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc23eec223966ae8f8873", "question": "Razzie awards are meant to go to bad movies, but who got nominated for directing the now widely respected film Scarface?", "answer": "Brian De Palma", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe52f451bf59ab7d2e38113", "question": "What direction does the Statue of Liberty face?", "answer": "Southeast", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b989", "question": "What is a \u2018half hunter\u2019?", "answer": "A pocket watch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feccad3ec223966ae8f889b", "question": "In 1948, which NBA basketball team did the Harlem Globetrotters defeat which eventually helped break the NBA's color barrier?", "answer": "Minneapolis Lakers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42f", "question": "Which country is home of the didgeridoos?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f16829f7c52aae91cc07c3", "question": "What expression is used to describe a child who closely resembles a parent?", "answer": "Chip off the old block", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b693", "question": "Until 2008, what color was the center square on a standard Scrabble board?", "answer": "Pink", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6607ba5bfecdd737e0834", "question": "What is the largest gathering of people in the world?", "answer": "The Kumbh Mela in India", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393ac", "question": "Who plays the role of Kissy Suzuki in the movie \"You Only Live Twice\"?", "answer": "Mie Hama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4fc", "question": "What do you get when you mix bourbon, mint and sugar?", "answer": "A Mint Julep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f755ea9e54d890926f70a", "question": "In Denmark, what is a Svangerskabsforebyggendemiddel?", "answer": "A condom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b8b701dd7bf43be5e7ed", "question": "A group of lizards is called what?", "answer": "A lounge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecdafeec223966ae8f88ef", "question": "What is the life span of a replicant in \"Blade Runner\"?", "answer": "Four years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea470cff048f679a45aba8", "question": "Based on Kepler's first law, the path of a planet is defined as what shape?", "answer": "Ellipse", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea4", "question": "What do sumo wrestlers throw into the ring to purify it before each bout?", "answer": "Salt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6b", "question": "The 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\" was based on what \"New York\" magazine article?", "answer": "Tribal Rites of the New Saturday Night", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ad", "question": "What does the \"PJ\" stand for in the name PJ Harvey?", "answer": "Polly Jean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a980561d1b4d384d5d68b", "question": "Boise is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Idaho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f7161a9e54d890926f6de", "question": "What is the capital city of Paraguay?", "answer": "Asuncion", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac78", "question": "Who invented the modern tire?", "answer": "John Boyd Dunlop", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600241d94be4723ccac2217e", "question": "In the book \"The Hunt for Red October,\" how is the Soviet submarine V. K. Konovalov destroyed?", "answer": "Reactor meltdown", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c5c2877e98cb977789b3", "question": "The \"Khyber Pass\" connects what two countries?", "answer": "Afghanistan and Pakistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe65689ae7e414034b5aecb", "question": "What year did the Battle of Agincourt take place?", "answer": "1415", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a789", "question": "Which US state borders most of Narrangansett Bay?", "answer": "Rhode Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0b2", "question": "Who was responsible for \"conducting\" the underground railroad rescuing slaves during the US Civil War?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b7", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives is buried beside him?", "answer": "Jane Seymour", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe12df1e39efa6330e0fed0", "question": "What is Europe's busiest cruise port?", "answer": "Barcelona, Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ef", "question": "When Forrest Gump was in the army, what sport was he good at?", "answer": "Ping Pong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d5", "question": "Who played \"Johnny Mnemonic\"?", "answer": "Keanu Reeves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a28c", "question": "Who is Metallica's drummer?", "answer": "Lars Ulrich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ac", "question": "Which city was the first to own a subway system?", "answer": "London", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984e", "question": "What is the name of the villain from the movie \"Mulan\"?", "answer": "Shan Yu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdab92a0b8cce1e6fda7053", "question": "The most popular car color in the USA for 2019 was which color?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a78e", "question": "What is the capital of Libya?", "answer": "Tripoli", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4de6206d333868d34d714", "question": "Who is known for running through the streets crying Eureka?", "answer": "Archimedes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c16f", "question": "Karakul, Dorset, Urial, and Jacob are types of what?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b32e", "question": "What was the leading cause of death in the late 19th century?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9cd", "question": "What is the more common term for sternum?", "answer": "Breastbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597ddf0577980686f722d181", "question": "What year was the first official soccer game played?", "answer": "1863", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf21", "question": "Tony Drago is a snooker professional from which country?", "answer": "Malta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338899", "question": "Who were the Three Musketeers?", "answer": "Arthos, Porthos, Aramis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db1", "question": "In \"The Fellowship of the Ring\", what does Gandalf do to the ring to make its secret inscription visible?", "answer": "Heat it in the fire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f98", "question": "What character from a pop song wears electric boots and a mohair suit?", "answer": "Bennie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339289", "question": "In the movie \"The Hunger Games\", who fights with a bow and arrow besides Katness?", "answer": "Glimmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca3", "question": "Oliver Mellors was the proper name of what D.H. Lawrence title character?", "answer": "Lady Chatterley's Lover", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afc2", "question": "The US Republican Party was originally established to fight for what cause?", "answer": "An end to slavery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3cd", "question": "What was the nationallity of Rasputin?", "answer": "Russian", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fb", "question": "What CBS sitcom aired Monday nights at 9 pm, from 1951 to 1957?", "answer": "I Love Lucy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339170", "question": "What popular Australian pop star sang the words \"All Beauty Must Die\"?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338df8", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek goddess Artemis?", "answer": "Diana", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c77d32d24f0f7a362efd553", "question": "What is the National Animal of Mauritius?", "answer": "The Dodo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefbf0b6ce05a3942286efa", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Material Girl\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a45f", "question": "The \"Carnac Stones\" are located what country?", "answer": "France", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe52f571bf59ab7d2e38114", "question": "What ingredient turns a martini into a dirty martini?", "answer": "Olive juice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd7d", "question": "Who was the first person to plant a vineyard in the Bible?", "answer": "Noah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b981", "question": "What used to be called the apple of love or love apple ?", "answer": "The tomato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eae", "question": "What screen legend made her final appearance in the movie \"Ship of Fools\"?", "answer": "Vivien Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bfdff78b668d7dfe168b5b8", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Jason's wife?", "answer": "Medea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ace", "question": "Who played Leon, Roseanne's boss at the caf\u00e9, on the sitcom \"Roseanne\"?", "answer": "Martin Mull", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b947", "question": "Which sport did hall-of-famer Larry Bird play?", "answer": "Basketball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b93c", "question": "Who did Charles Barkley name as \"the one player I'll accept losing to, if I have to lose\"?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e3c", "question": "Who played Stifler's mom in the American Pie movies?", "answer": "Jennifer Coolidge", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c530", "question": "At which pole would you find penguins?", "answer": "The South Pole", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0bc", "question": "Which film director's films include \"Raging Bull\" and \"Goodfellas\"?", "answer": "Martin Scorsese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa5880c73aa70ea0b70b3c", "question": "What is the name of the body of water that the Golden Gate Bridge transverses.", "answer": "John C. Fr\u00e9mont gave it the name \"Chrysopylae\" or \"Golden Gate\" on July 1, 1846.  The strait is commonly called \"Golden Gate\".", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4f", "question": "What LSU Tiger was drafted by the Orlando Magic in 1992?", "answer": "Shaquille O'Neal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6fd", "question": "Galveston, Mobile and Tampa are all located on the shores of what body of water?", "answer": "Gulf of Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a9", "question": "Who plays Richard Gere's lawyer in the movie \"Pretty Woman\"?", "answer": "Jason Alexander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c1d", "question": "What year saw the release of Disney's animated movie \"Cinderella\"?", "answer": "1950", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be21", "question": "George Fox is traditionally called the founder of what religious group?", "answer": "The Quakers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc91", "question": "What is the \"waltzing Matilda\" in the title of that traditional Australian song?", "answer": "A migrant worker's bedroll", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c575", "question": "What name is given to shellfish that cling to the bottom of ships?", "answer": "Barnacles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c8ac877e98cb977789ea", "question": "Where can you see the Great Stalacpipe Organ?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ec", "question": "What color is a Livestrong bracelet?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049be6cf93664eb10486a2", "question": "The \"Eisner Award\" is named after which influential cartoonist and writer?", "answer": "Will Eisner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3fd", "question": "The gopher is a member of what order of mammals?", "answer": "Rodents", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bba", "question": "For how many years were Madonna and Sean Penn married?", "answer": "4", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6661ca5bfecdd737e0865", "question": "Where is Apple Inc. headquartered?", "answer": "Cupertino, California", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5906814dff9c0647b50a8093", "question": "How old was novelist Harper Lee at the time of her death in February, 2016?", "answer": "89", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5956425b803c1f1ebcc4a02c", "question": "Tim McGraw and Faith Hill won the Academy of Country Music\u2019s very first Vocal Event trophy in 1997 for what song?", "answer": "\"It\u2019s Your Love\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca53", "question": "The rate of change of velocity is known as what?", "answer": "Acceleration", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee1", "question": "What bird was used as an alias for Tom Clancy's CIA agent in the Kremlin?", "answer": "The Cardinal", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba5e", "question": "What song, first used by FDR, has since become the unofficial theme song of the US Democratic party?", "answer": "Happy Days Are Here Again", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339188", "question": "In the TV show \"Futurama\", what was Uranus renamed to?", "answer": "Urectum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ec4a06d333868d34d763", "question": "What was the term for the official policy of racial segregation in South Africa until 1994?", "answer": "Apartheid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7b1", "question": "In what lunar phase is the moon when it is three-quarters full?", "answer": "Gibbous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b6", "question": "Who played Steve Urkel in the TV show \"Family Matters\"?", "answer": "Jaleel White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4e3", "question": "What fruit comes in Chubby Gray and Jubilee variety?", "answer": "Watermelons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76ca7eec85e375820b2d5", "question": "Which country borders Sweden only by bridge?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb2", "question": "What item would a tailor measure in lignes?", "answer": "A button", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b7a", "question": "What novel won John Steinbeck a Pulitzer Prize in 1940?", "answer": "Grapes of Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133996b", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what was the name of Comic Book Guy's dead dog?", "answer": "Chewbacca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b631", "question": "In NATO's phonetic alphabet, what is the letter \"A\" referred to as?", "answer": "Alpha", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388fd", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was warned that the cow was in the corn?", "answer": "Little Boy Blue", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e271fe83fe1f2a824b9f", "question": "Which country was the site of most of the Nazi extermination camps?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339620", "question": "What movie earned Francis Ford Coppola a Palme d'Or in 1979?", "answer": "Apocalypse Now", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d3", "question": "What US city gave birth to the Grasshopper cocktail?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a553823e1c6f9840ba31a5", "question": "James Alfred Wight was a famous author under which name?", "answer": "James Herriot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4a98e361d1b4d384d5d693", "question": "Which major lake is near the Ponderosa Ranch in the TV show \"Bonanza\"?", "answer": "Lake Tahoe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339465", "question": "Who wrote the movie \"Natural Born Killers\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f566d533a95c66dc4fe766", "question": "Which African capital city is named from the Greek meaning of \"three towns\"?", "answer": "Tripoli", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c815", "question": "What Italian physician was the first to describe the way the ovaries connect to the uterus in humans?", "answer": "Gabriele Falloppio", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febd9487e83c707845b2179", "question": "Who was the original \"Bozo the Clown\"?", "answer": "Vance \"Pinto\" Colvig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0f2", "question": "A light aircraft without an engine is called a what?", "answer": "Glider or a sailplane", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c699", "question": "What bird gets its pink color from the algae and shrimp it eats?", "answer": "The flamingo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a255", "question": "What country was Alfred Hitchcock born?", "answer": "England", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be17", "question": "What's the most common \"singing membranophone\"?", "answer": "The kazoo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef31f16ce05a3942286dfe", "question": "The Bronze Age was characterized by an alloy consisting of which two metals?", "answer": "Copper and tin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b699098e762b54eb9be9412", "question": "How is the number 20 written with Roman numerals?", "answer": "XX", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a43a", "question": "On which continent would you find gauchos?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b608", "question": "In what decade did the Vatican withdraw their requirement that Catholics refrain from eating meat on Fridays?", "answer": "The 1960s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b549", "question": "What is \"hotel-Dieu\" in France?", "answer": "A hospital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989ab04cb8751d53e7d7606", "question": "Who follows Godel and Escher in the title of a 1979 book by Douglas Hofstadter?", "answer": "Bach", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaee", "question": "Dodoma is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Tanzania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "594a63ef2ebb971c1417fb9f", "question": "Which famous classical composer's music was featured in the film \"Clockwork Orange\"?", "answer": "Beethoven's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c308", "question": "How long is the giraffe's tongue?", "answer": "17 inches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b81c", "question": "What color blazer is presented to the Masters golf winner?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e8d8fe83fe1f2a824be0", "question": "Who was the last king of the Plantagenet line of monarchs?", "answer": "Richard III", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc854c9abc30a8194e188aa", "question": "Who wrote the book \"The Perfect Storm\"?", "answer": "Sebastian Junger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60062a24c9d816e292245c14", "question": "Who painted \"The Persistence of Memory\"?", "answer": "Salvador Dal\u00ed -- \"The Persistence of Memory,\" aka \"The Melting Watches,\" is one of Dali's most recognizable works.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e6", "question": "Which company holds the ticker symbol \"FUN\" on the New York Stock Exchange?", "answer": "Cedar Point", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e43bfe83fe1f2a824baf", "question": "After the Battle of Kursk, the Germans did what?", "answer": "Began a lengthy retreat back to Germany.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe93c176bd93ce3a4e5f6a9", "question": "How often does your stomach manufacutre a new lining?", "answer": "Every three days", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1be", "question": "Lesley Hornby became more famous as who?", "answer": "Twiggy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e48", "question": "What word do we derive from the Salish Indian word for \"wild man\"?", "answer": "Sasquatch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a5", "question": "What is the middle part of an atom called?", "answer": "Nucleus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008fdfcf842fa4c4ba96c1", "question": "What century did John Milton write the epic poem \"Paradise Lost\"?", "answer": "17th Century", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b340", "question": "Who was the first woman to fly the Atlantic alone?", "answer": "Amelia Earhart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c3", "question": "What name is given to the unit of electrical resistance?", "answer": "Ohm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59774232284458f1d785441e", "question": "What church in Georgia has produced the films \"Flywheel\", \"Facing the Giants\", \"Fireproof\", \"Courageous\",and \"War Room\"?", "answer": "Sherwood Baptist Church, Albany, Georgia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7689deec85e375820b2a3", "question": "Which US state has the most national parks?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b153", "question": "On Christmas Day 800 A.D., who was coronated as emperor of the Holy Roman Empire?", "answer": "Charlemagne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feddb0a6ce05a3942286d8d", "question": "What is the name of the famous Christmas Carol sung by Mariah Carey?", "answer": "\"All I Want for Christmas Is You\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d115314fea7fe947a22264", "question": "Who produced the Beatles' \"Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band\" album?", "answer": "George Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fffa6e873838c5c8a417f33", "question": "Which is the most dangerous tree in the world?", "answer": "Manchineel tree (Found in the Florida Everglades and coastal Caribbean, its sap will cause blisters with the slightest contact.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b60", "question": "What is the highest female voice in a choir?", "answer": "Soprano", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a64a", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Natural State\"?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60078bab0eee65b76b9f266b", "question": "For what is Matthew Webb famous?", "answer": "He was the first man to swim the English Channel.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a77b", "question": "What city, located on the Mississippi River, is known as \"The Gateway to the West\"?", "answer": "St. Louis", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd1", "question": "What duo's biggest hits are found on 1985's \"Songs from the Big Chair\" album?", "answer": "Tears for Fears", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c0", "question": "From 1948 to 1950, the Fender Telecaster was known by what alternate name?", "answer": "Broadcaster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fbaed8f0738315b1fb74e31", "question": "What spell was used to trick the Goblet in \"Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire\"?", "answer": "Confundus Charm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339517", "question": "Who was the actress murdered while taking a shower in the 1960 movie \"Psycho\"?", "answer": "Janet Leigh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339baa", "question": "Whose daughter have Eagles been searching for, in their #1 hit song \"One of These Nights\"?", "answer": "The Devil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601600e0fe83fe1f2a824c59", "question": "What was the name of the first at-home film camera?", "answer": "Kodak #1", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad43", "question": "Which country seized the USS Pueblo after accusing its American crew of unlawful spying in 1968?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a015", "question": "What actor was the narrator in the movie \"Alive\"?", "answer": "John Malkovich", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cde06e347d002c297e4f7", "question": "Who wrote the classic science fiction novel \"Helliconia Summer\"?", "answer": "Brian W. Aldiss", "category": "arts"}]